HOGAN McDONALD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

651-230-1107 hpeter.mcdonald@icloud.com github.com/HoganMcDonald

Dear Hiring Manager at Ackmann & Dickenson

I am writing to express interest in the Software Engineer opening you have listed. I am a recent Full Stack Developer graduate from Prime Digital Academy in Minneapolis, and I am excited about pursuing a future in software development. Before finding my passion in software, I worked as an ordained minister at a small, progressive church in St. Paul. While there, I learned that I was passionate about work that impacts people's lives in a positive way. At Prime, the project I spent the largest amount of time on was an industrial internet of things platform for Lab651 in St. Paul. The platform was called Praeco. Here are a few links with more information:

http://lab651.com/lab-651-keystone-automation-practical-industrial-iot-solution/ https://tech.mn/news/2017/06/09/st-paul-based-lab651-keystone-automation-for-joint-iot-venture/

I am interested in challenging development tasks and am hungry to continually learn and grow. During the early weeks of my time at Prime academy, I chose to tackle a complicated problem. While our curriculum was focused on learning how to properly write loops of different varieties, I decided to try writing a pathfinding application in JavaScript. I was doing practice problems in JavaScript on my own time when I came across a problem that required me to write a program that could find the shortest distance between two points on a grid while avoiding obstacles. I knew immediately that the problem was far more complicated than I was prepared to take on, but I decided to tackle it anyways. After a few weeks of effort, I was able to produce a working website.

A link to my work can be found here: https://github.com/HoganMcDonald/pathFinding
The live app is here: https://hogan-pathfinder.herokuapp.com/

I am comfortable woking directly with clients and have experience articulating complex issues to non-technical people. A major part of my ministerial training involved communication. Oftentimes the focus of my study was incredibly dry. My job was to take ancient texts written with ancient audiences in mind, provide historical context, and make appropriate applications to modern life. This forced me to constantly challenge my own assumptions about my listeners perspectives. In order to provide meaningful teaching that helped people in their day to day lives, I had to constantly work on becoming a more empathic and vulnerable communicator.

I am very interested in your company and this position. I would love to talk more about Ackmann & Dickenson and the Engineering team. I am available during normal business hours Wednesday through Friday of this week, this Saturday the 26th, or in the evenings any time this or next week. Please let me know if any of those times are a possibility to talk more.

Thank you, Hogan McDonald

HOGAN McDONALD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

651-230-1107

hpeter.mcdonald@icloud.com

github.com/HoganMcDonald

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack web developer motivated by creative problem-solving, technological exploration, and human-centered design. I enjoy using new and interesting technologies to solve real-world problems. My background is in pastoral ministry which involves formal education in organizational leadership, research, and communication. I am constantly driven to improve myself and the world around me through the use of technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- MEAN stack
- MongoDB
- Express.js
- AngularJS
- Node.js

- ES6/7
- Object Oriented
- Development
- Git
- JQuery
- Gulp

- NPM
- Passport
- PostgreSQL
- IBM Watson
- Heroku
- Particle.io

EDUCATION

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY

4/2017 - 8/2017

Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

METRO STATE UNIVERSITY

9/2015 - 8/2016

Generals - Spiritual Engagement and Community Leadership

NORTH CENTRAL UNIVERSITY

9/2013 - 9/2015

Generals - Pastoral Studies

EXPERIENCE

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY

3/2017 - 8/2017

Full Stack Engineering Student

I chose to attend prime because I knew that I learned best in an immersive environment. Prime offered the intense experience I knew represented the best entry point into the industry for me.

Solo Project - Capture

A mobile-first web application that enables content creators to write great speeches and blogs.

- Technologies used in development include Angular, PostgreSQL, SASS, Node.js, Express.js, and Gulp.
- It allows users to capture moments of inspiration when they happen and then organize those thoughts later.
- Capture utilizes the IBM Watson API, data visualization tools, and a genetic algorithm used to suggest ways of organizing content.

Capture-content.herokuapp.com

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Group Project - Praeco - Lab651

Praeco is a mobile first web application written in the MEAN stack designed to connect users in to their IOT devices leveraging the particle.io platform.

- Technologies I focused on include Node.js, Express.js, Passport, MongoDB, Nodemailer, Twilio, Particle.io, NPM, and Heroku.
- Once an admin invites a user to join, they are able to set up text message and email alerts for their IOT devices connected through Particle.io.
- I focused on back end logic for this project which included setting up notification services and connecting them to requests received directly from IOT devices via particle webhooks.

lab651.com

[WORDS] BOOKSTORE

5/2016 - 4/2017

Store Lead

I worked in collaboration with business owners to open a first-of-its-kind independent bookstore in the MSP airport.

My responsibilities included:

- Maintaining store inventory information.
- Creating visual displays for new merchandise.
- Training employees on visual standards for the store.
- Training new employees on opperational standards for the company.
- Designing and selling merchandise for the store.

BLOOM CHURCH

5/2015 - 3/2016

Community Engagement Coordinator

While at Bloom, I was ordained as a minister and would regularly deliver sermons to a group of 30 - 50 people.

Other responsibilities included:

- Maintaining online content including church website, weekly newsletter, podcasts, and google ads.
- I wrote a small group curriculum that more than 50 people have now participated in.
- I also participated in occasional counceling of individuals and couples. whybloom.com